Wrangling and EDA are sometimes used anonymously because their purposes often overlap.
تستخدم Wrangling وEDA في بعض الأحيان دون الكشف عن هويته لأن أغراضهم تتداخل في كثير من الأحيان.
In this course, when I say wrangling it means you'll be gathering,
في هذه الدورة التدريبية، عندما أقول "wrangling" يعني أنك ستجمع
assessing, and cleaning your data,
بياناتك وتقيمها وتنظفها،
but the modifications you make when cleaning the dataset won't make your analysis,
لكن التعديلات التي تجريها عند تنظيف مجموعة البيانات لن تجعل تحليلاتك
visualizations, or models better, they just make them work.
أو مرئيات أو نماذجك تبدو بشكل أفضل، إنما هي تجعلها تعمل فقط.
Alternatively, EDA means you'll be exploring and augmenting
بدلاً من ذلك، فإن EDA تعني أنك ستستكشف وتزيد
your data to maximize the potential of your analysis, visualizations, and models.
بياناتك لزيادة إمكانات التحليلات والمرئيات والنماذج الخاصة بك.
One example is engineering new features or moving outliers,
من الأمثلة المستخدمة هندسة الميزات الجديدة أو نقل القيم الشاذة،
they can make visualisations more impactful,
التي تجعل المرئيات أكثر تأثيراً،
for instance, removing outliers to zoom into the heart of
فعلى سبيل المثال، إزالة القيم الشاذة لتكبير مركز
a distribution or they can improve a models R-squared value.
التوزيع أو التي يمكنها تحسين القيمة التربيع لنماذج R.
We'll dive into this in more detail later in the class,
سنتناول هذا بمزيد من التفاصيل في وقت لاحق في الفصل،
but we'll take a first pass now.
لكننا الآن سنأخذ نظرة عابرة.
And remember, don't worry if you don't get everything right away.
وتذكروا بأنه لا ينبغي عليكم القلق إذا لم تحصلوا على كل شيء في الوقت الحالي.
We have entire courses that cover each of these steps.
لدينا دورات تدريبية كاملة تغطي كل خطوة من هذه الخطوات.